058-458-6484 (Israel) 201-994-6484 (US) ari.abramowitz1@gmail.com

# **Ari Abramowitz** Full Stack Web Developer

ariabr.netlify.app linkedin.com/in/ariabr github.com/ariabr

# **Summary**

Full stack web developer with experience in both startup and agile environments. I am a creative, organized and methodical problem solver with strong writing skills and a background in philosophy. I have a drive to learn new technologies and I am always ready for a new challenge and the opportunity to bring another product to life.

# **Skills**

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend / Databases: Python, Django, Flask, Node, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Express, Firebase

Other Tools: Git, GitHub, Bash, Heroku, Jasmine, Pytest, Jira, Trello

# **Experience**

### Fullstack Software Engineer | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2020 - Present

- · Approved code for deployment across 15+ projects
- · Developed software to streamline AR management for 80,000+ residents in 80 facilities throughout the US
- · Improved efficiency of lab processing 2,000+ COVID tests per day by building an app to track sample history
- · Contributed to the process of transforming business requirements into actionable tickets
- · Improved code quality by performing initial and final code reviews for a team of 10 developers
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

### **Software Developer | Taryag Analytics**

2019 - 2020

- · Primary developer for a text mining and analytics startup
- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing the frontend and backend for 6 new analysis features, including a sentence structure analyzer, a word cloud generator, and multiple text comparison tools
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data

#### **Powered by Sefaria Contest**

2020

- · Frontend developer for team building a 3D family tree visualizer for the Powered by Sefaria contest
- · Awarded Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project on the company's website

# **Projects**

2018 - 2020

- · Ezrat Nashim DB: Crowdsourced database designed to help users assess local synagogue options
- · Spotifake: Frontend music player application
- · Slag: Chat app where users can sign in, create rooms and read, send, edit and delete messages
- · Tirred: Discussion board where users sign up, add posts and vote and comment on posts

### **Open Source**

2020

· Mindful Internet Use: Coded bug fix for Chrome productivity extension with 400+ users

· Built 5 cloud-hosted web-apps as part of an 8-month apprentice-style coding bootcamp

#### **Education**

#### **Continuing Education**

		0010
•	The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)	2020
•	Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival)	2021
•	Bash Mastery: The Complete Guide to Bash Shell Scripting (Ziyad Yehia, Udemy)	2021

### **Bloc | Web Developer Track**

2019

 Mastered fundamental principles of software engineering and web development through project-based learning

### Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- $\cdot\;$  Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success